{   "data": [
{
"id":"1",
"question":"HTML stands for",
"option1":"Hyper Text Markup Language",
"option2":"High Tech Markup Language",
"option3":"Hyper Text Makeup Language",
"option4":"High Tech Makeup Language",
"answer":"Hyper Text Markup Language"
},

{
"id":"2",
"question":"A program which translates a high-level language program into a machine language program is called ?",
"option1":"Compiler",
"option2":"Interpreters",
"option3":"Both (A) and (B)",
"option4":"None of the above",
"answer":"Both (A) and (B)"
},

{
"id":"3",
"question":" A sequence of instructions in a computer language to get the desired result is known as :",
"option1":"An algorithm",
"option2":"A decision table",
"option3":"A program",
"option4":"None of the Above",
"answer":"A program"
},

{
"id":"4",
"question":"Which type of errors are flagged by Compilers ?",
"option1":" Logical errors",
"option2":"Syntax errors",
"option3":"Both (A) and (B)",
"option4":"None of the Above",
"answer":"Syntax errors"
},

{
"id":"5",
"question":" An algorithm is best described as :",
"option1":"A computer language",
"option2":"A step by step procedure for solving a problem",
"option3":"A branch of mathematics",
"option4":" None of the above",
"answer":"A step by step procedure for solving a problem"
},

{
"id":"6",
"question":"Bug means :",
"option1":" A logical error in a program",
"option2":"A difficult syntax error in a program",
"option3":"Both (A) and (B)",
"option4":"None of the above",
"answer":"Both (A) and (B)"
},

{
"id":"7",
"question":"The part of a machine level instruction which tells the central processor what has to be done ?",
"option1":"An operation code",
"option2":"An address",
"option3":"An operand",
"option4":"None of the above",
"answer":"An operation code"
},

{
"id":"8",
"question":"Which of the following is not true about an interpreter?",
"option1":"Interpreter generates an object program from the source program.",
"option2":"Interpreter is a kind of translator",
"option3":"Interpreter analysis each source statement every time it is to be executed.",
"option4":"None of the above",
"answer":"None of the above"
},

{
"id":"9",
"question":"The errors that can be pointed out by the compiler are :",
"option1":"Syntax errors",
"option2":"Semantic errors",
"option3":"Logical errors",
"option4":"None of the above",
"answer":"Syntax errors"
},

{
"id":"10",
"question":"Which of the following statement is not true?",
"option1":"FORTRAN is a high-level language.",
"option2":"A FORTRAN program written for the IBM-PC, is totally different from a FORTRAN program written in for the execution of SUN machine.",
"option3":"FORTRAN is extensively used to write programs for programming scientific computations.",
"option4":"None of the above",
"answer":"A FORTRAN program written for the IBM-PC, is totally different from a FORTRAN program written in for the execution of SUN machine."
},

{
"id":"11",
"question":"A program that converts a high level language program to a set of instructions that can run on a computer is called a :",
"option1":"Compiler",
"option2":"Debugger",
"option3":"Editor",
"option4":"None of the above",
"answer":"Compiler"
},

{
"id":"12",
"question":"The name given to a sequence of instructions in a computer language to get the desired result is :",
"option1":" A program",
"option2":"An algorithm",
"option3":"A pseudocode",
"option4":"A decision table",
"answer":" A program"
},

{
"id":"13",
"question":"The language understood by a computer with out translation is called :",
"option1":"Command language",
"option2":"High-level language",
"option3":"Assembly language",
"option4":"Machine language",
"answer":"Machine language"
},

{
"id":"14",
"question":"The mapping from assembly language instructions into machine language instructions is",
"option1":"Many-one",
"option2":"One-many",
"option3":"One-one",
"option4":"Many-many",
"answer":"One-one"
},

{
"id":"15",
"question":"A compiler is :",
"option1":"A machine-independent and OS-independent",
"option2":"Machine-dependent and OS-dependent",
"option3":"Machine-dependent and OS-independent",
"option4":"Machine-independent and OS-dependent",
"answer":"Machine-dependent and OS-dependent"
},

{
"id":"16",
"question":"Which one of the following statements is incorrect?",
"option1":"A compiler compiles the source program.",
"option2":"An assembler takes an assembly program as input.",
"option3":"A compiler does the same type of function as interpreter.",
"option4":"None of these",
"answer":"A compiler does the same type of function as interpreter."
},

{
"id":"17",
"question":"A translator which reads an entire program written in high-level and converts it into machine language code is :",
"option1":"Assembler",
"option2":"Translator",
"option3":"Compiler",
"option4":"System software",
"answer":"Compiler"
},

{
"id":"18",
"question":"Which of the following is not one of the process that a high-level language program must go through before it is ready to be executed?",
"option1":"Translation",
"option2":"Controlling",
"option3":"Loading",
"option4":"Linking",
"answer":"Controlling"
},

{
"id":"19",
"question":"Which of the following is related to machine language ?",
"option1":"Difficult to learn",
"option2":"First generation language",
"option3":"Machine dependent",
"option4":"All of the above",
"answer":"All of the above"
},

{
"id":"20",
"question":"The language C is:",
"option1":"An assembly language",
"option2":"A third generation high-level language",
"option3":"A machine language",
"option4":"None of the above",
"answer":"A third generation high-level language"
},

{
"id":"21",
"question":" C compiler traps :",
"option1":"Logical errors",
"option2":"Syntax errors",
"option3":"Both (A) and (B)",
"option4":"None of these",
"answer":"Both (A) and (B)"
},

{
"id":"22",
"question":"Who is father of C Language?",
"option1":"Bjarne Stroustrup",
"option2":"Dennis Ritchie",
"option3":"James A. Gosling",
"option4":"Dr. E.F. Codd",
"answer":"Dennis Ritchie"
},

{
"id":"23",
"question":"Sign to comment line in Python",
"option1":"# comment line",
"option2":"// comment line",
"option3":"* comment line",
"option4":"",
"answer":"# comment line"
},

{
"id":"24",
"question":"The sign '#' of the compiler directive must appear at the ______ of a line",
"option1":"Beginning",
"option2":"Middle",
"option3":"End",
"option4":"None of the above",
"answer":"Beginning"
},

{
"id":"25",
"question":"Which committee standardize 'C' programming language?",
"option1":"ANSI",
"option2":"W3C",
"option3":"TRAI",
"option4":"ISO",
"answer":"ANSI"
},

{
"id":"26",
"question":"What is the maximum length of a Python identifier?",
"option1":"32",
"option2":"16",
"option3":"128",
"option4":"No fixed length is specified",
"answer":"No fixed length is specified"
},

{
"id":"27",
"question":"Who developed Python Programming Language?",
"option1":"Wick van Rossum",
"option2":"Rasmus Lerdorf",
"option3":"Guido van Rossum",
"option4":"Niene Stom",
"answer":"Guido van Rossum"
},

{
"id":"28",
"question":"Which type of Programming does Python support?",
"option1":"object-oriented programming",
"option2":"structured programming",
"option3":"functional programming",
"option4":"all of the mentioned",
"answer":"all of the mentioned"
},

{
"id":"29",
"question":"Is Python case sensitive when dealing with identifiers?",
"option1":"no",
"option2":"yes",
"option3":"Machine dependent",
"option4":"None of the Above",
"answer":"no"
},

{
"id":"30",
"question":"Which of the following is the correct extension of the Python file?",
"option1":".python",
"option2":".pl",
"option3":".py",
"option4":".p",
"answer":".py"
},

{
"id":"31",
"question":"Which of the following is the correct extension of the HTML file?",
"option1":".ht",
"option2":".hml",
"option3":".html",
"option4":".hlml",
"answer":".html"
},

{
"id":"32",
"question":"All keywords in Python are in _________.",
"option1":"Capitalized",
"option2":"lower case",
"option3":"UPPER CASE",
"option4":"None of the Above",
"answer":"None of the Above"
},

{
"id":"33",
"question":"Which of the following is used to define a block of code in Python language?",
"option1":"Indentation",
"option2":"Key",
"option3":"Brackets",
"option4":"All of the mentioned",
"answer":"Indentation"
},

{
"id":"34",
"question":"Which keyword is used for function in Python language?",
"option1":"Function",
"option2":"Def",
"option3":"Fun",
"option4":"Define",
"answer":"Def"
},

{
"id":"35",
"question":"What does pip stand for python?",
"option1":"unlimited length",
"option2":"all private members must have leading and trailing underscores",
"option3":"Preferred Installer Program",
"option4":"None of the Above",
"answer":"Preferred Installer Program"
},

{
"id":"36",
"question":"Which of the following is true for variable names in Python?",
"option1":"underscore and ampersand are the only two special characters allowed",
"option2":"unlimited length",
"option3":"all private members must have leading and trailing underscores",
"option4":"None of the Above",
"answer":"unlimited length"
},

{
"id":"37",
"question":"Which of the following is the truncation division operator in Python?",
"option1":"|",
"option2":"//",
"option3":"/",
"option4":"%",
"answer":"/"
},

{
"id":"38",
"question":"Which of the following functions is a built-in function in python?",
"option1":"factorial()",
"option2":"print()",
"option3":"seed()",
"option4":"sqrt()",
"answer":"print()"
},

{
"id":"39",
"question":"Which of the following is the use of id() function in python?",
"option1":"Every object doesn't have a unique id",
"option2":"Id returns the identity of the object",
"option3":"All of the mentioned",
"option4":"None of the mentioned",
"answer":"Id returns the identity of the object"
},

{
"id":"40",
"question":"Which of the following is not a core data type in Python programming?",
"option1":"Tuples",
"option2":"Lists",
"option3":"Class",
"option4":"Dictionary",
"answer":"Class"
},

{
"id":"41",
"question":"What is HTML?",
"option1":"HTML describes the structure of a webpage",
"option2":"HTML is the standard markup language mainly used to create web pages",
"option3":"HTML consists of a set of elements that helps the browser how to view the content",
"option4":"All of the mentioned",
"answer":"All of the mentioned"
},

{
"id":"42",
"question":"Who is the father of HTML?",
"option1":"Rasmus Lerdorf",
"option2":"Tim Berners-Lee",
"option3":"Brendan Eich",
"option4":"Sergey Brin",
"answer":"Tim Berners-Lee"
},

{
"id":"43",
"question":"Which of the following is used to read an HTML page and render it?",
"option1":"Web server",
"option2":"Web network",
"option3":"Web browser",
"option4":"Web matrix",
"answer":"Web browser"
},

{
"id":"44",
"question":"Which of the following is not a difference between HTML and XHTML?",
"option1":"Charset in both html and xhtml is 'text/html'",
"option2":"Tags and attributes are case-insensitive in HTML but not in XHTML",
"option3":"Special characters must be escaped using character entities in XHTML unlike HTML",
"option4":"Charset in html is 'text/html' where as in xhtml it is 'application/xml+xhtml'",
"answer":"Charset in both html and xhtml is 'text/html'"
},

{
"id":"45",
"question":"What is DOM in HTML?",
"option1":"Language dependent application programming",
"option2":"Hierarchy of objects in ASP.NET",
"option3":"Application programming interface",
"option4":"Convention for representing and interacting with objects in html documents",
"answer":"Convention for representing and interacting with objects in html documents"
},

{
"id":"46",
"question":"In which part of the HTML metadata is contained?",
"option1":"head tag",
"option2":"title tag",
"option3":"html tag",
"option4":"body tag",
"answer":"head tag"
},

{
"id":"47",
"question":"Which of the following is not the element associated with the HTML table layout?",
"option1":"alignment",
"option2":"color",
"option3":"size",
"option4":"spanning",
"answer":"color"
},

{
"id":"48",
"question":"Which element is used for or styling HTML5 layout?",
"option1":"CSS",
"option2":"jQuery",
"option3":"JavaScript",
"option4":"PHP",
"answer":"CSS"
},

{
"id":"49",
"question":"HTML is a subset of ___________.",
"option1":"SGMT",
"option2":"SGML",
"option3":"SGME",
"option4":"XHTML",
"answer":"SGML"
},

{
"id":"50",
"question":"Which character is used to represent when a tag is closed in HTML?",
"option1":"#",
"option2":"!",
"option3":"/",
"option4":"\\",
"answer":"/"
},

{
"id":"51",
"question":"What is CSS?",
"option1":"CSS is a style sheet language",
"option2":"CSS is designed to separate the presentation and content, including layout, colors, and fonts",
"option3":"CSS is the language used to style the HTML documents",
"option4":"All of the mentioned",
"answer":"All of the mentioned"
},

{
"id":"52",
"question":"Which of the following CSS selectors are used to specify a group of elements?",
"option1":"tag",
"option2":"id",
"option3":"class",
"option4":"both class and tag",
"answer":"class"
},

{
"id":"53",
"question":"Which of the following has introduced text, list, box, margin, border, color, and background properties?",
"option1":"HTML",
"option2":"CSS",
"option3":"PHP",
"option4":"Ajax",
"answer":"CSS"
},

{
"id":"54",
"question":"Which of the following CSS framework is used to create a responsive design?",
"option1":"django",
"option2":"rails",
"option3":"larawell",
"option4":"bootstrap",
"answer":"bootstrap"
},

{
"id":"55",
"question":"Which of the following CSS selector is used to specify a rule to bind a particular unique element?",
"option1":"tag",
"option2":"id",
"option3":"class",
"option4":"both class and tag",
"answer":"id"
},

{
"id":"56",
"question":"Which of the following CSS property is used to make the text bold?",
"option1":"text-decoration: bold",
"option2":"font-weight: bold",
"option3":"font-style: bold",
"option4":"text-align: bold",
"answer":"font-weight: bold"
},

{
"id":"57",
"question":"Which of the following CSS style property is used to specify an italic text?",
"option1":"style",
"option2":"font",
"option3":"font-style",
"option4":"@font-face",
"answer":"font-style"
},

{
"id":"58",
"question":"Which of the following are the CSS Extension Prefixes for Webkit?",
"option1":"-chrome",
"option2":"-web",
"option3":"-o-",
"option4":"-webkit",
"answer":"-webkit"
},

{
"id":"59",
"question":"Which of the following is the first CSS specification to become an official W3C Recommendation?",
"option1":"CSS level 2",
"option2":"(X)HTML CSS",
"option3":"CSS level 1",
"option4":"CSS level 2.1",
"answer":"CSS level 1"
},

{
"id":"60",
"question":"Which of the following function defines a linear gradient as a CSS image?",
"option1":"gradient()",
"option2":"linear-gradient()",
"option3":"grayscale()",
"option4":"image()",
"answer":"linear-gradient()"
},

{
"id":"61",
"question":"Which of the following CSS property can be used to set the image as a border instead of the border style?",
"option1":"background-image-source",
"option2":"background-image",
"option3":"border-image-source",
"option4":"border-image",
"answer":"border-image-source"
},

{
"id":"62",
"question":"Which of the following CSS property defines the different properties of all four sides of an element's border in a single declaration?",
"option1":"border-width",
"option2":"padding",
"option3":"border",
"option4":"border-collapse",
"answer":"border-width"
},

{
"id":"63",
"question":"NFT stands for",
"option1":"Non-fungible token",
"option2":"Non-functioning token",
"option3":"New file token",
"option4":"News file token",
"answer":"Non-fungible token"
},

{
"id":"64",
"question":"What is the capital of India",
"option1":"Bhopal",
"option2":"Delhi",
"option3":"Kota",
"option4":"Amritsar",
"answer":"Delhi"
},

{
"id":"65",
"question":"What is the capital of Pakistan",
"option1":"Islamabad",
"option2":"Lahor",
"option3":"Dhaka",
"option4":"Tazakistan",
"answer":"Islamabad"
},

{
"id":"66",
"question":"Capital of the state of Arunachal Pradesh",
"option1":"Kohima",
"option2":" Itanagar",
"option3":"Dispur",
"option4":"Tawang",
"answer":"Itanagar"
},

{
"id":"67",
"question":"capital of the state of Haryana",
"option1":"Kurukshetra",
"option2":"Chandigarh",
"option3":"Faridabad",
"option4":"Gurgaon",
"answer":"Chandigarh"
},

{
"id":"68",
"question":"Capital of the state of Bihar",
"option1":"Jaipur",
"option2":"Bhopal",
"option3":"Patna",
"option4":"Raipur",
"answer":"Patna"
},

{
"id":"69",
"question":"Capital of the state of Madhya Pradesh",
"option1":"Ujjain",
"option2":"Indor",
"option3":"Lucknow",
"option4":"Bhopal",
"answer":"Bhopal"
},

{
"id":"70",
"question":"Capital of the state of Uttar Pradesh",
"option1":"Chandauli",
"option2":"Varansi",
"option3":"Lucknow",
"option4":"Kanpur",
"answer":"Lucknow"
},

{
"id":"71",
"question":"Capital of the state of Punjab",
"option1":"Jalandhar",
"option2":"Chandigarh",
"option3":"Amritsar",
"option4":"Kapurthala",
"answer":"Chandigarh"
},

{
"id":"72",
"question":"capital of the state of Assam",
"option1":"Guwahati",
"option2":"Shillong",
"option3":"Dispur",
"option4":"Itanagar",
"answer":"Dispur"
},

{
"id":"73",
"question":"capital of the state of Chhattisgarh ",
"option1":"Bhopal",
"option2":"Rachi",
"option3":"Dehra Dun",
"option4":"Raipur",
"answer":"Raipur"
},

{
"id":"74",
"question":"capital of the state of Orissa",
"option1":"Cuttack",
"option2":"Bhubaneshwar",
"option3":"Puri",
"option4":"Patna",
"answer":"Bhubaneshwar"
},

{
"id":"75",
"question":"capital of the state of Maharashtra",
"option1":"Nagpur",
"option2":"Aurangabad",
"option3":"Mumbai (Bombay)",
"option4":"Pune",
"answer":"Mumbai (Bombay)"
},

{
"id":"76",
"question":"capital of the state of Meghalaya",
"option1":"Shillong",
"option2":"Dispur",
"option3":"Cherrapunji",
"option4":"Guwahati",
"answer":"Shillong"
},

{
"id":"77",
"question":"headquarters of the union territory, Chandigarh",
"option1":"Chandigarh",
"option2":"Amritsar",
"option3":"Ludhiana",
"option4":"Jalandhar",
"answer":"Chandigarh"
},

{
"id":"78",
"question":"capital of the state of Tamil Nadu",
"option1":"Bangalore",
"option2":"Madurai",
"option3":"Hyderabad",
"option4":"Chennai (Madras)",
"answer":"Chennai (Madras)"
},

{
"id":"79",
"question":"capital of the state of Gujarat",
"option1":"Gandhinagar",
"option2":"Baroda",
"option3":"Rajkot",
"option4":"Ahmedabad",
"answer":"Gandhinagar"
},

{
"id":"80",
"question":"capital of the state of Sikkim",
"option1":"Thimphu",
"option2":"Gangtok",
"option3":"Darjeeling",
"option4":"Imphal",
"answer":"Gangtok"
},

{
"id":"81",
"question":"Winter capital of the state of Jammu & Kashmir",
"option1":"Gulmarg",
"option2":"Jammu",
"option3":"Kargil",
"option4":"Srinagar",
"answer":"Jammu"
},

{
"id":"82",
"question":"capital of the state of Himachal Pradesh",
"option1":"Manali",
"option2":"Kullu",
"option3":"Shimla",
"option4":"Dalhousie",
"answer":"Shimla"
},

{
"id":"83",
"question":"capital of the state of Mizoram",
"option1":"Lunglei",
"option2":"Aizawl",
"option3":"Imphal",
"option4":"Agartala",
"answer":"Aizawl"
},

{
"id":"84",
"question":"headquarters of the union territory, Dadra & Nagar Haveli",
"option1":"Kavaratti",
"option2":"Daman",
"option3":"Nashik",
"option4":"Silvassa",
"answer":"Silvassa"
},

{
"id":"85",
"question":"capital of the state of Andhra Pradesh",
"option1":"Secunderabad",
"option2":"Rajahmundry",
"option3":"Hyderabad",
"option4":"Vishakhapatnam",
"answer":"Hyderabad"
},

{
"id":"86",
"question":"capital of the state of Karnataka",
"option1":"Mangalore",
"option2":"Mysore",
"option3":"Chennai",
"option4":"Bangalore",
"answer":"Bangalore"
},

{
"id":"87",
"question":"capital of the state of Rajasthan",
"option1":"Udaipur",
"option2":"Jaipur",
"option3":"Jaisalmer",
"option4":"Ajmer",
"answer":"Jaipur"
},

{
"id":"88",
"question":"headquarters of the union territory, Pondicherry",
"option1":"Cuddalore",
"option2":"Nagapattinam",
"option3":"Karaikal",
"option4":"Pondicherry",
"answer":"Pondicherry"
},

{
"id":"89",
"question":"capital of the state of Manipur",
"option1":"Kohima",
"option2":"Bishnupur",
"option3":"Imphal",
"option4":"Agartala",
"answer":"Imphal"
},

{
"id":"90",
"question":"summer capital of the state of Jammu & Kashmir",
"option1":"Gulmarg",
"option2":"Srinagar",
"option3":"Jammu",
"option4":"Leh",
"answer":"Srinagar"
},

{
"id":"91",
"question":"capital of the state of West Bengal",
"option1":"Durgapur",
"option2":"Kharagpur",
"option3":"Kolkata (Calcutta)",
"option4":"Bhubaneshwar",
"answer":"Kolkata (Calcutta)"
},

{
"id":"92",
"question":"headquarters of the union territory, Daman & Diu",
"option1":"Surat",
"option2":"Diu",
"option3":"Daman",
"option4":"Silvassa",
"answer":"Daman"
},

{
"id":"93",
"question":"capital of the state of Goa",
"option1":"Margao",
"option2":"Marmagao",
"option3":"Panaji",
"option4":"Vasco da Gama",
"answer":"Panaji"
},

{
"id":"94",
"question":"Which is the smallest state of India",
"option1":"Rajasthan",
"option2":"Assam",
"option3":"Goa",
"option4":"Punjab",
"answer":"Goa"
},

{
"id":"95",
"question":"capital of the state of Kerala",
"option1":"Kochi",
"option2":"Ernakulam",
"option3":"Kozhikode",
"option4":"Thiruvananthapuram",
"answer":"Thiruvananthapuram"
},

{
"id":"96",
"question":"headquarters of the union territory, Lakshadweep",
"option1":"Port Blair",
"option2":"Cannanore",
"option3":"Kavaratti",
"option4":"Silvassa",
"answer":"Kavaratti"
},

{
"id":"97",
"question":"headquarters of the union territory, Andaman & Nicobar Islands",
"option1":"Indira Point",
"option2":"Silvassa",
"option3":"Port Blair",
"option4":"Kavaratti",
"answer":"Port Blair"
},

{
"id":"98",
"question":"capital of the state of Tripura",
"option1":"Agartala",
"option2":"Udaipur",
"option3":"Aizawl",
"option4":"Imphal",
"answer":"Agartala"
},

{
"id":"99",
"question":"50 + 25 =",
"option1":"25",
"option2":"65",
"option3":"75",
"option4":"80",
"answer":"75"
},

{
"id":"100",
"question":"25 + 10 + 12 =",
"option1":"47",
"option2":"40",
"option3":"57",
"option4":"52",
"answer":"47"
}
]}
